STEPHEN WU

Senior Blockchain Engineer

**** +1 760 565 3493

@ zbitkut@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/stephen-wua17481231

https://stephen-wu.vercel.app/

O Scarborough, Toronto, Canada

SUMMARY

Enthusiastic, spirited blockchain developer with 5+ years of experience in building decentralized applications and ecosystems. Implemented a number of applications and solutions using various technologies and programming languages. Delving into EVM and Rust related Blockchain fields to master them. Eager and willing to acquire any other latest technologies.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

01/2022 - 01/2024 •

Blockchain Developer

New York, CA

MLG Blockchain

MLG Blockchain is a global blockchain consulting & development firm based in Toronto and New York City.

- Designed and Created smart contracts for Binary Options Trading Platform on Arbitrum One
- Built self-hosted **Oracle** System for token prices
- Implemented Diamond Proxy Pattern(Multi-Facets Proxy) overcoming the 24KB size limit of smart contract
- Improved **SEO** score from 28 to 97
- Charged Fees For Secondary Sales by implementing **ERC2981** NFT royalty standard.

11/2020 - 10/2021

Lead Developer

San Francisco, CA

Slime Finance

Slime Finance is an advanced profit-sharing DeFi protocol aiming to go multi-chain, consisting of our own Automated Market Maker, NFT marketplace, yield-optimising vaults and wide variety of pools and farms. Our end goal is to become the go-to multi-chain DeFi hub satisfying all your DeFi needs.

- Developed its MultiDEX contracts and a lottery contract for their holders while ensuring smart contract security by implementing best practices such as access control and input validation to prevent potential attacks such as reentrancy and overflow.
- Built and deployed NFT staking contracts on BSC Network for \$SLIM rewards because of ensuring faster and cheaper transactions for users.
- Conducted smart contract **audits** to identify and address potential security vulnerabilities
- Validating the lottery backend for security and fairness of the game with off-chain VRF
- Implemented Diamond Proxy Pattern(Multi-Facets Proxy) overcoming the 24KB size limit of smart contract

04/2020 - 10/2020

Blockchain Developer

Singapore, Singapore

Enjin (Intern)

Enjin offers a suite of integrated products that make non-fungible tokens (NFTs) easy for individuals, businesses, and developers.

- Collaborated with the development team to design and implement various features for Enjin's platform.
- Developed smart contracts using Solidity and integrating them into the Enjin ecosystem.
- Built RESTful APIs to connect the frontend and backend of Enjin's applications.
- Wrote clean, maintainable code that adhered to industry best practices.
- Conducted unit tests and debugging to ensure the quality and functionality of the codebase.

EDUCATION

2016 - 2020

Bachelor's degree of Computer Science Singapore Institute of Technology

Singapore, Singapore

CV Enhancy

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JS/TS Rust Move Solidity C/C++ **Python** LangChain **Machine Learning**

React / Angular / Vue.js SQL / NoSQL **Agile Methodology & SCRUM**

PROJECTS

Aneroverse NFT Collection

https://opensea.io/collection/official-aneroverse

- · Created a Smart Contract for NFT minting site using ERC721A, resulting in 1,388 ETH of Total Volume.
- Built a NFT Airdrop site with whitelisting feature using MerkleTree.
- Designed Tokenomics and software design patterns and built the R2R MVP platform, including a job marketplace and social media platform, resulting in profit of 400 ETH
- Tech-Stack: Solidity, Hardhat, React, Typescript, Nest.js, Mocha/Chai

Crypto Betting Platform (Binary Options)

Ryze.fi is a decentralized binary options platform that allows users to speculate on the price movements of crypto assets.

- Implemented Diamond Pattern(Multi-Facet Proxy)
- Built our own Oracle System for price feeds from several Central Exchanges
- Built a Subgraph system
- Tech-Stack: Solidity, Hardhat, Nest.js, React, Subgraph, Mocha/Chai

DeSuiLabs Coinflip

- · Implemented the coinflip smart contract with on-chain random generation with Move language
- · Built the sleek UI with Next.js
- · Used Shinami gas station to solve the extremely high throughput of users' gameplay
- · Tech-Stack: Move, Next.js, Express.js, Sui-core

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

Competitive Programming

https://leetcode.com/cocodev/ https://www.codechef.com/users/coco

https://codeforces.com/profile/byteroa d1177

Desui CoinFlip

Built and managed the most famous coinflip game which has 50k+ active players per day and 1M+ Sui daily volume on Sui network

FTSO Top 10 Provider

Participated in a FTSO system as one of active providers for one community on Flare/Songbird Network and developed an exclusive price forecasting algorithm which is powered by ML and various regressions.

Aneroverse NFT Collection

Developed a smart contract using solidity and ERC721A, to raise 400 ETH and 1388 ETH volume on Opensea